In the last video,
在上个视频中
you saw this line of Python that computes the sum of 3 and 5.
你看到了这行 Python 代码 它会求 3 和 5 的和
The plus sign and this line is an arithmetic operator.
这行代码中的加号是一个算术运算符
Python has several arithmetic operators
Python 具有多个算术运算符
most of which follow the usual rules of Mathematics.
大多数运算符都遵守数学规则
Let's look at the first four,
我们来看看前四个运算符
in Python addition and subtraction are performed with the usual symbols, plus and minus.
在 Python 中 我们使用普通的加号和减号进行加减运算
Multiplication uses an asterisk,
乘法使用星号
and division uses a forward slash.
除法使用斜杠
Here you can see that multiplication happens before addition.
在此处 可以看出乘法发生在加法之前
This is because Python follows
因为 Python 遵守数学运算顺序
Mathematical Order of Operations which you can get a refresher on in the notes below.
你可以参阅下方的注释 复习这方面的知识
If you want addition to come first,
如果你希望先算加法
you can enclose this part in parentheses.
可以将这部分放在括号里
Moving on from those four,
看完这四个运算符后
here's the operator for exponentiation.
再看看取幂运算符
You can raise one number to the power of another with two asterisks.
你可以使用两个星号计算一个数字和另一个数字的幂
For example, this line prints three to the power of two which results in nine.
例如 这行会输出 3 的 2 次幂
There's another operator that is sometimes
另一个运算符是插入符号
mistaken for the exponentiation operator. The caret.
有时候会被错误地当成取幂运算符
This actually performs a more obscure operation called bitwise XOR.
它实际上会执行一种更复杂的运算 叫做按位 XOR
This is an arithmetic operator that doesn't follow the usual rules of Mathematics.
这个算术运算符并不遵守一般的数学规则
Bitwise operators are not something you need to know for this course but,
在这门课程中 你不需要了解按位运算符
if you're interested there's information about this in the notes below.
但是如果你感兴趣的话 可以在下面的注释中了解相关信息
All you need to remember is that if you perform exponentiation,
你只需记住 如果要取幂
you use two asterisks and not with
则使用两个星号 而不是插入符号
a caret or you'll accidentally produce very confusing results.
否则会不小心生成很奇怪的结果
Another useful operator is this percent sign which performs the modulo operation.
另一个实用运算符是这个百分号 它会执行取模运算
It returns the remainder after you've divided the first number by the second.
当你用第一个数字除以第二个数字后 它会返回余数
In this example, nine divided by two is four with a remainder of one.
在这个示例中 9 除以 2 的结果是 4 余数为 1
So this line would print one since modulo gives us the remainder.
因此这行代码会输出 1 因为取模运算返回的是余数
You might also find use for integer division denoted by two forward slashes.
你可能还会用到整数除法 用两个斜杠表示
It divides one integer by another but rather than giving the exact answer,
它将一个整数除以另一个整数 但是不会给出精确答案
it rounds down the answer down to an integer.
而是将结果向下取整数
Seven divided by two is three point five which rounds down to three.
7 除以 2 是 3.5 向下取整为 3
Notice it rounds down even if the answer is negative.
注意 即使答案是负数 也会向下取整
In this case, negative three point five was rounded down to negative four.
在这种情况下 -3.5 向下取整为 -4
There are other categories of operators that we'll learn about
我们很快会学习其他类别的运算符
soon but these are all the arithmetic operators in Python.
这些就是 Python 中的所有算术运算符